真希望我能让你改主意  凯茜
I really wish I could have changed your mind, Cathy.
-我...  -因为
- I just... - Because, you know...
这对你实在没好处
you know, this is just not good for you.
跟委员会的谈判
The negotiations with the committee
实在还太远
are just too far down the road.
你答应见我是因为你聪明
Well, you agreed to see me because you're smart.
因为你是该有所疑虑
Because doubt is what you should be having.
凯茜  我尊敬你
Look, Cathy, I respect you.
否则我们也不会在一起这么久了
We wouldn't have lasted as long together if I didn't.
我丈夫在等我呢
My husband's waiting for me.
但你会出丑的
But you're gonna be made to look a fool.
没必要侮辱我  弗兰西斯
There's no need to insult me, Francis.
会有一堆证人反驳
Witness after witness is gonna rebut
你要说的一切
whatever you have to say.
我的证词就是那样
My testimony is what it is.
公众舆论会自有公断
It'll all be resolved in the court of public opinion.
是啊  但公众会信谁呢
Yes, but who is the public going to believe?
你  还是恐怖分子电脑上的爆炸物残留
You or explosive residue on a terrorist's computer?
凯茜  你的证词会看上去像小气的报复
Look, Cathy, your testimony's gonna seem petty and vengeful.
那你会怎么样啊  还有什么前途
And then where is that gonna leave you? What prospects?
太迟了
It's too late.
-你得栽一跟头  -什么
- You need to take a fall. - Excuse me?
委员会得等等
Look, the committee is just gonna have to wait.
反正再过两周这都会过去
In two weeks, it's gonna be over anyway,
你就站错队了
and you're gonna be on the wrong side of this thing.
-走着瞧吧  -是啊
- Well, we'll see. - Yes, we will.
你先请
After you.
但我的话是真心的  凯茜
But I meant what I said, Cathy.
凯茜
Cathy?
救命  救命  国务卿摔倒了
Help! Help! The secretary has fallen!
人人影视倾情奉献
翻译   草草
翻译   国士章鱼X
翻译   苏小黛
翻译   杏仁斯嘉丽
时间轴   知之
时间轴   壬虚浪影
后期   饿得慌
顾问   老杜
校对   草草
总监   草草
纸牌屋
第五季  第十二集
你真走运
You're a lucky bastard.
直到今晚结束时才是
Oh, not until the end of the night.
或者该说早上了
Or should I say, the morning.
凯瑟琳·杜兰特摔倒了  怎么回事
Catherine Durant fell? How?
人会摔倒  就这么简单
Well, people fall. That's what they do.
是啊  在需要的时候
Yes, they fall when they need to.
你的新朋友还是会被弹劾的
Your new friend is still gonna get impeached.
希望到时候
Well, I hope I can still count on
参议员还是会支持我
the good senator's support when the time comes.
你很会打牌  马克
You're a good card player, Mark.
你从不在牌桌上谈公事
You never talk shop at the table.
总是提款的时候才说
It's always when you're cashing out.
我妈妈教得好
Well, my mother raised me well.
票数让参议员越来越难做了
The numbers are getting harder and harder for the senator.
-为什么  -资金流入  电话打来
- Why is that? - The money and the calls coming in.
一个数字减少  另一个就增多
One number goes down, and the other one goes up.
参议员受到了压力  来自哪里
The senator's feeling the heat, from where?
你回头再来吧  我们到时谈
Why don't you come in later. We can talk about it then.
不不  等一下
No, no, no. Wait a minute.
丹尼  我指着他的票呢
Danny... I'm counting on his vote.
-那别指望了  -不行
- Well, you can count it out. - No. No...
半数民主党都是如此
And half of the Democrats as well.
别去想什么警告了  众议院还未就
Forget about censure, the House hasn't even voted yet
弹劾状表决呢
on articles of impeachment.
你不是唯一在做参议院工作的人
You're not the only one working the Senate.
-有人想赶走弗兰西斯  -我问是谁
- Someone wants Francis out. - And I'm asking you who.
你混了很久了
You've been around a long time.
没人会告诉你怎么投票
Nobody tells you how to vote.
只会说你不听他们的会有什么下场
They just tell you what happens if you don't go their way.
石油每桶50美元
Oil's at $50 a barrel.
没人对此满意
Nobody's happy with that.
我们本打算今天对司法委员会
We were hoping to bring you live coverage
听证会进行直播
of the judiciary hearing today.
但由于杜兰特国务卿
But given the postponement
意外地无法出席  而使听证会延期
due to Secretary Durant's unexpected absence,
我们将改为
we'll be switching to
转播军事委员会的会议
the Armed Services Committee meeting instead,
-女士  -多位军队高官
- Ma'am? - where several top military officials...
将报告哈里发国愈增的威胁
...are citing the increased threat of ICO...
今天的日程
Today's schedule.
我觉得您会想看这个
And I thought you might wanna see this.
是汤姆·耶茨的信
It's a note from Tom Yates.
另外
Oh, and reminder,
我们得继续士兵康复项目
we have to get back to the Soldier Recovery Project.
[标题]
汤姆·耶茨著
和平
Peace.
那是我们的目标
That's our goal.
通过和平  我们得找到新的前进之途
And through peace, we must find a different way forward.
伊斯玛特上校是民主派领袖
Colonel Ismat is the leader of the Democratic faction,
竭力解放叙利亚人民
dedicated to freeing the Syrian people.
由于杜兰特国务卿暂时无法继续工作
And since Secretary Durant is temporarily sidelined,
我今天要暂代她  因为美国政府
I'm stepping in today because the American government
支持一切迈向稳定的坚实脚步
supports any concrete steps toward stability.
如果得到确认  叙利亚冲突中
If it is determined that chemical or biological weapons
用到了生化武器
have been used in the Syrian conflict,
那么从此刻起
then from this moment forward,
美国将有道德义务插手
the United States will be morally obligated to intervene.
所以  叙利亚总统算就此得到警告了
So, the Syrian president should consider himself on notice.
总统先生  鉴于众议院
Mr. President, given the potential outcome
可能提交弹劾状
that the House will affirm articles of impeachment,
现在插手中东冲突合适吗
is this the right time to wade into a Middle Eastern conflict?
这个问题与主题无关  但我还是回答吧
Well, the question's off subject, but I'll answer it.
首先  投票就不会进入参议院
First of all, the vote is never gonna get to the Senate.
这只是毫无意义的党争闹剧
It's a senseless partisan circus.
我的关注点是做好我的工作
My focus is to remain doing my job,
也就是确保美国人民繁荣富强
which is to ensure prosperity for the American people,
并努力实现
and to try to achieve...
对不起  和平怎么说的来着
I'm sorry, how did you say it again? Peace?
-和平  -和平
- Salam. - Salam...
这就是我们在努力争取的  和平
That's what we're trying to broker here. Salam.
我们给总统和伊斯玛特上校时间会面吧
So let's give the president time to meet with Colonel Ismat.
我会在媒体接待室接受提问
I'll take follow-up questions in the press briefing room.
或许我太没想象力  但那就是夜晚的大海啊
Maybe I'm being too literal, but that's the sea at night.
-你喜欢吗  -我更喜欢红的
- Do you like it? - I prefer the reds.
我在泰特现代艺术馆看过他的展出
I... I saw a show of his at the Tate Modern.
但我无法把人和艺术品分开
I have trouble separating the man from the art, though.
他是个压抑的人  你肯定也知道
He was, uh, depressive, as I'm sure you know.
你能看出他在抵抗心魔
You can see him fighting his demons.
纳泽先生到了
So Mr. Nasser has arrived?
到了  在四季酒店等我的电话
Uh, here and waiting for my call at the Four Seasons.
我就是觉得这恐怕不好
Well, I just... I don't think it's a good idea
我们政府的一位成员
for anyone in our administration
去见哈里发国的成员
to be meeting with a member of ICO.
他不是成员
He's not a member.
他跟尤瑟夫·艾哈迈迪是同学
He went to school with Yusuf Al Ahmadi.
他是律师  他代理人和组织
He's a lawyer. He represents people, organizations.
-就一个组织  -而且他是要见我
- One organization, to be exact. - And he's meeting with me.
为什么有这样的犹豫
Where is all this hesitation coming from?
对不起  我头好疼
I'm sorry. I just have a splitting headache.
胡蔓藤
Gelsemium.
治偏头痛的  我经常犯
For migraines. I get them all the time.
是中药
It comes out of China.
别担心  是草药
But don't worry, it's herbal.
但你得注意用量
You have to be careful of the dosing, though.
就两滴
Just two drops.
我看到的是纯粹的感觉
You know, it's pure feeling for me.
光明对黑暗
Light versus dark.
和他们的交界线
And that line where they meet.
总统根本不知道
The president had no idea.
你跟麦卡伦先生很亲密
You were close to Mr. Macallan?
是的  但那不代表我知道他的企图
Yes, but that doesn't mean that I knew what he was up to.
那你怎么知道总统与此无关
But then how do you know the president wasn't involved?
我是最后见到艾丹的人  他向我坦白了
I was the last person to see Aidan. He confessed to me.
他秘密利用了国安局和外国情报监视法法庭
He secretly used the NSA, FISA,
操纵了选民
to manipulate the electorate.
我们要会见律师
We're meeting with counsel
打磨剩下的证词
to perfect the rest of the testimony.
只要没人能拿出驳斥你的证据就行
As long as no one has anything that contradicts you.
不会有的
No one does.
回来的感觉好吗  莉安
Does it feel good to be back, LeAnn?
是的  谢谢
It does. Thank you.
我知道克莱尔很高兴
Well, I know Claire is delighted
你能回到她办公室
to have you back in her office.
副总统的会面
Will you let me know as soon
一结束你就告诉我
as  the vice president's meeting is done?
好  先生
Yes, sir.
我讨厌她回来  她撒谎
I hate having her back. She's a liar.
你觉得麦卡伦给了她什么做保险吗
You think Macallan gave her something for insurance?
她不肯承认  但是的  我觉得有
She won't admit it. But, yeah, I think he did.
等委员会启动后  让她去作证吧
Let's get her in front of that committee when they're up and running.
到时她就必须决断了
Then she'll have to make a choice.
格林有些不敢作证
Green is hesitant to testify.
要不是我知道
You know, if I didn't know better,
我会以为他是泄密者呢
I'd think he was the leak.
他知道的信息
He has far more information
实在太多了
than anyone should be comfortable with.
另外理查德森参议员还没回我电话
Also, Senator Richardson hasn't called me back.
上校  抱歉刚刚不得不走开
Colonel, my apologies for the interruption.
我想向你保证  你的担忧就是我的担忧
And I want to assure you that your concerns are my concerns.
艾哈迈迪兄弟
The Ahmadi brothers...
他们所想的激进伊斯兰是维持不下去的
their idea of radical Islam is unsustainable.
纳泽代表了厌倦了死亡的哈里发国分子
Nasser represents members of ICO who are tired of death.
他们基本上控制了
They essentially control
多个油田和多家精炼厂
numerous oil fields and several refineries.
纳泽已经见过了叙利亚总统
Nasser already met with the president of Syria.
还有佩特罗夫的外交部长
And Petrov's minister of foreign affairs.
他想做个交易
He's looking for a deal.
他们想在这个十年内成为
They wanna be a corporation trading on the Dow
上市公司
before the decade is over.
他们想加入石油输出国组织
They wanna be a part of OPEC.
那么伊斯玛特上校和叙利亚人民呢
So where does that leave Colonel Ismat and the Syrian people?
能保命  只要我们调兵
Alive... once we're on the ground.
是啊  但俄罗斯已被请去  我们需要理由
Yes, but Russia was invited in. We need cause.
叙利亚总统用毒气对付了人民
The Syrian president has gassed civilians.
他还会再那么做的  我敢保证
He will again. I can guarantee it.
伊斯玛特上校会确保这一点
Colonel Ismat will make sure of it.
他会在政权内部煽动袭击
He'll instigate an attack from the regime.
我们派部队过去  不动哈里发国的资源
We put troops on the ground, leave ICO resources alone...
纳泽会确保他们配合
and Nasser will make sure they cooperate.
怎么了
What is it?
你担心他会被弹劾吗
Are you afraid he's gonna be impeached?
因为  他很可能会的
'Cause there's a good chance that he will be.
这就是你想等的原因吗  因为
Is that why you wanna wait? 'Cause...
我可以推迟一切
I can make it all wait.
戴维斯女士和我的谈话很有成效
Ms. Davis and I had a very productive talk.
我告诉了她
I let her know that
我们的插手是以艾哈迈迪的被捕为交换条件的
our involvement is contingent on the delivery of Ahmadi.
是啊  但我能采取行动的时间
Yes, but the window is closing for me
越来越少了
to be able to act on this.
司法委员会可不会等
Judiciary's not gonna wait.
想要这个起作用  时不我待
For this to be effective, it has to be now or never.
我会让她联络纳泽先生
I'll have her reach out to Mr. Nasser.
那另一件事呢
And, uh, what about the other matter?
莉安吗
You mean LeAnn?
戴维斯女士今天下午会跟她谈
Ms. Davis will speak to her later this afternoon.
你听到总统的话了
You heard the president.
我还在白宫
Uh, I'm still at the White House.
-等我们插手叙利亚  -先生
- Once we get into Syria... - Sir,
我是肖恩·杰弗瑞斯
my name is Sean Jeffries.
-我跟...  -嗯  我知道你是谁
- I work with... - Yes, I know who you are.
肖恩
Sean...
我知道汤姆·汉默施密特在查什么
I know what Tom Hammerschmidt is working on.
杰弗瑞斯先生  如果你想预约  我可以安排
Mr. Jeffries, if you need an appointment, I can arrange one...
先生  我只想占用您片刻时间
Sir, if I could. Just a moment of your time.
是机密
It's confidential.
如果你不介意  我们想用一下这个房间
Oh, if you don't mind, we'd like this room for a moment.
给你30秒  但你开始前
You have 30 seconds. But before you start,
是我错了吗  格雷森先生不是你的上级吗
am I mistaken, or is Mr. Grayson your superior?
是的  对不起  但是
Yes, I'm sorry, but...
汤姆认为  道格·斯坦普和您  先生
Tom thinks Doug Stamper and yourself, sir,
跟佐伊·巴恩斯之死有关
are somehow involved with the death of Zoe Barnes.
汉默施密特先生得到了一部
And Mr. Hammerschmidt has a phone
有人给巴恩斯小姐的手机
that was given to Ms. Barnes.
手机只打过一个号码  是您的号码
It called only one number, and that number was yours.
看来这个号码
Now, it seems that number
在她死时带的手机里也有
has shown up on the phone that she died with.
虽然手机受损  但现在有技术
It was damaged, but there's technology now
可以让他们获取她死前
that will give them access to the data
手机上的数据
leading up to the day of her death.
内存  电话  短信
Its internal memory. Calls, texts.
都在上面
It's all there.
你什么时候开始为我们工作的
When did you start with us?
一周前
A week ago.
是副总统让你加入的
And it was the vice president who brought you on?
是的
That's correct.
一周
A week...
你已经
and you're already having
跟总统谈机密了
confidential conversations with the president.
是的
I am.
如果你再听到别的消息  直接来找我
If you hear anything else, you come directly to me.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
不管你怎么说  这是伪证罪
Whatever you say it is, it's perjury.
伪证
Oh, perjury, huh?
这是你的底线吗
That's where you draw the line?
我不干了
I'm done.
案子已经准备好了
The case has already been prepared.
穆罕默德·卡拉比的电脑上找到了熵炸药
TATP was found on Muhammed Kalabi's computer.
杜兰特国务卿怎么想根本不重要
It doesn't matter what Secretary Durant believes or not.
一个是推测  一个是事实
One is speculation, and the other is fact.
事实  是吗  那是事实吗
Fact? Really? Is that what it is?
如果听上去像事实  那就是事实
If it sounds like a fact, then it is a fact.
卡拉比键盘上有爆炸残留物
Kalabi had explosive residue on his keyboard.
你知道联调局其他人都受够总统了
You know the rest of the bureau is done with the president.
我没跟他们说话  我在跟你说话
I'm not talking to them. I'm talking to you.
他们都睁一只眼闭一只眼  但还能持续多久
They've looked the other way, but for how much longer?
道格  他完了
Doug... he's done.
那我怎么办
Where does that leave me?
这就是我们在谈的
That's what we're discussing right now.
你知道总统怎么想吗
Do you know what the president thinks?
他觉得你是泄密者
He thinks you're the leak.
那倒好了
I wish.
我给你点时间收回那句话
I'm going to give you a moment to take that statement back.
我会做我该做的  我去作证
I'll do what I have to do. I'll testify.
但总统完了
But the president is done.
他在失去支持  你能感觉到
He's losing support. You can smell it.
你在给别人效力吗
Are you working for anyone else?
-你在给别人效力吗  -没有
- Are you working for anyone else? - No.
我也不想知道别的
And I don't wanna know anything else.
我已知的已经让我烦透了
I'm tired of what I know.
就当我是个传话的
Consider me a proxy.
-什么  -他们不想问  但我来问
- What? - They don't wanna ask, but I will.
你必须完全投入
You need to be fully committed,
也就是说  你得完全透明
which means being fully transparent,
也就是说  你得交出你手上的东西
which means handing over what you have.
能拜托你等等吗
Slow down, will you, please?
我想回家了  戴维斯女士
I'd like to get home, Ms. Davis.
莉安  莉安
LeAnn? LeAnn?
有时候  我会去宾馆过夜
Some nights, I go to a hotel to sleep,
就为了换换地方  不在家待着
just to get out of my apartment.
这个城市的女人  都要高度警惕
Being a woman in this city, the vigilance it takes...
你不能犯任何错误  不能有一丝分神
You're not allowed to make a mistake... get distracted.
代价很沉重
It's a heavy price.
神经紧绷年复一年
To be on the edge that way for years and years...
我的证词不会让人失望的
My testimony won't disappoint.
就算总统和副总统满意吧
Well, the president and vice president are pleased, I assume.
但你觉得还要多久
But how long before the media
媒体就会开始追问麦卡伦的死
starts asking questions about Macallan's death,
以及他怎么死的
and how he was killed?
顺便说一句  你的枪在我这里
I have your gun, by the way.
-晚安  -没错  晚安
- Good night. - Yes, good night.
克莱尔
Claire?
-怎么了  -克莱尔
- Yes? - Claire?
什么事
What's the matter?
汉默施密特又有了个新理论
Hammerschmidt has a new theory.
他认为道格·斯坦普和我杀了佐伊·巴恩斯
He thinks Doug Stamper and I killed Zoe Barnes.
他们可能接触到了我的手机短信内容
They may have access to my cell phone, to my texts.
白宫有人在向汉默施密特泄密
Someone in this White House is talking to Hammerschmidt
现在又是这个
and now this.
道格啊
Oh, Doug.
可怜的道格
Poor Doug.
是啊
Yes.
他怎么这么倒霉
He's an unlucky person.
他一直如此
Always has been.
先生  参议员的支持动摇了
Sir, the senator's support is wavering.
道格  我是克莱尔
Doug, it's Claire.
抱歉  我...
I'm sorry, I...
弗兰西斯和我在想
Francis and I were wondering
你明晚能不能到宅邸来一趟
if you could come up to the residence tomorrow evening.
吃个晚饭
For dinner.
最近发生了这么多事
It'll give us a chance to
我们也好歇一歇  喘口气
take a breath with all that's been happening.
喂
Hello?
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
-你是谁  -拜托  你肯定猜到了吧
- Who is this? - Come on, you must know by now.
-我不知道  -艾丹·麦卡伦
- No, I don't. - Aidan Macallan.
查查他是怎么利用外国情报监视法裁决的
Look into how he used and abused the FISA ruling.
我们怎么认识的
How do we know each other?
别问了
Now come on.
如果我告诉你
If I told you that,
我还要怎么继续帮你
how can I possibly keep helping you?
你难道不希望我帮你吗
And don't you want me to help you?
可我们在哪见面  告诉我这个就行
But where do we meet? Just give me that.
-泥巴里  -等等
- In the muck. - Wait.
佐伊·巴恩斯的死不是意外
Zoe Barnes' death was not an accident.
道格·斯坦普杀了她
Doug Stamper killed her.
但你已经知道了
But you already know that.
不  别挂  别挂
No, don't hang up. Don't hang up.
司法委员会可能
The Judiciary Committee may be
还希望杜兰特国务卿尽快恢复
hoping Secretary Durant recovers.
但全世界都在关注
But the rest of the world is waiting to see
佩特罗夫嘲笑安德伍德所划红线
叙利亚总统将如何回应
how the Syrian president responds
安德伍德总统划下的红线
to President Underwood's line in the sand.
与此同时  莫斯科称总统此份声明
Moscow, meanwhile, calls the president's statements,
是"即将倒台之人的绝望之举"
"The desperate act of a man on his way out of office."
你和你哥哥还有联系吗
Are you in contact with your brother?
没有
No.
也就周末吧  偶尔过过生日
Sundays. Occasional birthday.
我还以为你们两个要更亲近些
I thought you were closer than that.
没有  只有有麻烦时我们才会找对方
No. We usually only speak when one of us is in trouble.
所以我才打听一下
Well, that's why I ask,
因为越是这种时候  我们就越需要支持
'cause in times like these, we all need support.
我会请律师
Well, I'll have counsel.
不  你得请最好的律师
No, you'll have the best lawyers.
什么都得最好的  顶尖的
The best of everything. The best.
你还想再来些鱼吗
Would you like some more fish?
不了  谢谢
No, thank you.
《先驱报》手里的料都只是间接的
Whatever the Herald has is circumstantial.
当然
Of course.
没人知道她到底遭遇了什么
No one knows what really happened to her,
永远也不会有人知道
and no one ever will.
是这样  道格
But, look, Doug...
今晚我和克莱尔请你来的原因
The reason that Claire and I invited you over tonight
是因为我们希望你知道你对我们多么重要
is because we want you to know how much you mean to us.
对我们两个都是
To both of us.
好  先生
Yes, sir.
在我们说别的事之前
Before we say anything else,
我们只想明白无误地确认
we just wanted to be absolutely certain that...
你知道这一点
you knew that.
当然
Of course.
我们要面临的
What we're up against,
这个政府要面临的
what this administration is facing...
也是我要面临的
Well, what I'm facing...
即便我们都相信
Even though both of us believe that
我被起诉的可能微乎其微
there's very little chance that I could ever be indicted,
我们仍然
we still...
得想办法
have to find a way to
彻底解决这整件事
remove this entire issue from the table.
我不能再跟这事有牵连了
I just can no longer be associated with this.
我会辞职  并继续处理此事
I'll resign while I'm dealing with this.
我觉得这可能还不够
I think this is going to require more than that.
我会发表声明
Well, I'll make a statement...
说这是人身攻击式的政治手段
and blame it on the politics of personal destruction.
不  道格  恐怕这些仍不够
No, Doug, I'm afraid that's just not going to be enough.
我们得转移怀疑目标
We have to shift... the suspicion.
我们需要你...
We need you to...
我们需要你让自己跟佐伊·巴恩斯的死挂上钩
We need you to implicate yourself in the death of Zoe Barnes.
先别激动  听我说
Now, before you react, just listen.
目前你是最有可能的人选
You are the most likely candidate at this point.
你当时心烦意乱  还酗酒
You were distraught, you were drinking.
我说不好
The... I don't know.
我们会编一些事出来  然后泄漏出去
We'll make up some story, and then we'll leak it.
你忠心耿耿  你那么做是为了我
You... you were loyal, you did it for me.
你忠诚过了头  采取了极端手段
You were too loyal. You went too far.
然后  到最后  毫无疑问
And... and then, in the end, there'll be no question...
我失陪一下好吗
Can you excuse me?
生日快乐
这要么是哪个怪胎想搏头条
Well, it's either a crank looking for a headline,
要么就是内部人士在说真话
or someone on the inside telling the truth.
你感觉是什么
What's your sense?
他知道生日卡的事
He knew about the birthday cards.
我说不好
I don't know.
也许重点在于这电话
Maybe the story is the call.
那些闪存盘  泄密本身
The flash drives. The leaks themselves.
如果我们点出泄密的事
If we call out the leaks,
他可能就不会再联系我了
he may stop contacting me.
还有麦卡伦的事  那真是条线索吗
And the Macallan business, is that even a real lead?
这些网站什么都不会承认的
None of these sites will admit to anything.
因为这太丢人了
Because it's an embarrassment.
多个选情对安德伍德不利的郡的
An overwhelming amount of Underwood material
社交媒体用户  爆出了大量
was reported by social media users in counties
安德伍德的材料
that he was expected to lose.
但我联系的所有人
But anyone I reach out to
都不想谈论此事
does not wanna be talking about this.
泄密者说那是未经授权的国内监控
The leak said it was unauthorized domestic surveillance.
政府只需要搬出"恐怖活动"
All the administration has to say is "terror,"
看起来就正当了
And they seem justified.
他可不是在铲除恐怖分子
He wasn't rooting out terrorists.
他是想赢得选举
He was trying to win an election.
国务卿正好撞了头可太巧了
And very convenient that the Secretary of State hits her head.
你现在听起来像是阴谋论...
Now you sound like a conspiracy...
我不是阴谋论者
I'm not a conspiracy theorist.
我试图想象他是怎么想的
I try to imagine what it's like inside his mind,
如果我是他  我会怎么做
what I would do if I were him.
我跟你们说  这是各种...
And I'm telling you, it is all sorts of...
他没有意识形态  没有道德方向
He has no ideology. No North Star.
这难道不是最可怕的吗
Isn't that the scariest thing of all?
汤姆  你觉得佐伊·巴恩斯是被谋杀的吗
Tom, do you think Zoe Barnes was murdered?
一个27岁的人失足撞上火车的概率有多大
How often does a 27-year-old fall in front of a train?
-那好吧  我们去证明它  -好
- All right, then. Let's prove that. - All right.
怎么了
What's wrong?
道格·斯坦普的办公室来电了
Doug Stamper's office called.
他们想安排见面
They wanna set up a meeting.
尽快吧
Soon as possible.
这是好事
This is good.
不管你男友今早从你手机里读到了什么
Whatever your boyfriend read off your phone this morning
都传到了正确的人的耳朵里
made its way to the right person.
我不知道我还能坚持多久
I don't know how much longer I can do this.
你只是在骗一个骗子
You're lying to a liar.
你无法从佐伊死时的手机上得到任何信息
You can't get anything off the phone Zoe died with.
他们只要相信我们能做到就行了
They just need to believe we can.
这到底是什么工作
What is this job?
跟以前不一样了
Not what it used to be.
我不希望你反应过度
I don't want you to overreact.
但汤姆一直在继续写作
But Tom kept writing.
看来他终于完成他的书了
It seems he finally finished his book.
而且他暗示了一些事
And he alludes to things.
什么叫"暗示了一些事"
What do you mean "Alludes to things"?
我不知道  相关行都被涂黑了
I don't know. Lines are blacked out.
就像被编辑过
It's like it's redacted.
时不时的有一些段落
There are paragraphs here and there...
你跟他说过什么
What did you tell him?
他知道些什么
What does he know?
他给任何人看过吗  寄给过任何人吗
Has he shown this to anyone? Sent it to anyone?
-出版商  媒体  -我不知道
- Publishers, the press? - I don't know.
那你知道什么
Well, what do you know?
我来处理他  我只是想跟你说一声
I will handle him. I just wanted you to be aware.
-妈了个逼的  -我说了我会处理的
- Son of a bitch. - I said I'll take care of it.
不  我来处理
No, I'll take care of it.
你躲得远远的
You stay a million miles away from this.
你怎么会这么蠢
How could you be so stupid...
动了真情
to fall in love?
这事还没提交表决
This thing isn't on the floor yet,
我们就已经失去参议员的支持了
and we're losing senators.
失去了几个吧  不过
We're losing some maybe, but...
参院最讨喜的地方也是我最讨厌的地方
What I like about the Senate is what I hate.
传染性
It's contagious.
只要一个人有了什么想法
One of 'em gets an idea,
立马就会像流感一样传遍全院
and it spreads through the body like a flu.
我再想想办法
I'll look into it.
总共就100个人  我们只需要过半
There's 100 of 'em. All we need is half.
我能躺下吗
Can I just lay down?
-最好不要  -我就躺几分钟
- I don't think that's a good idea. - Just for a few minutes.
我他妈快累死了  我得想想
I'm just so fucking tired, and I need to think.
你得想什么
Why do you need to think?
他给你的那些东西  你拿在手里越久
The longer you hang on to whatever he gave you,
你的处境就越危险
the more danger you're in.
你错看局势了
You're reading this wrong.
你以为那是保险  其实不是
You think it's some kind of insurance, but it's not.
莉安
LeAnn...
不管总统出了什么事
Whatever happens to the president,
都不是你  或者我的错
it's not your fault, or mine.
-你以为我无关紧要吗  -我可没这么说
- You don't think I make a difference? - I didn't say that.
还是你觉得我不够投入
You don't think that I'm dedicated enough?
太投入了
Too dedicated.
过了就有问题了  会让你一叶障目
That can be a problem. That can make you blind.
你根本不知道
You have no idea...
我做了不可原谅的事  莉安
I've done something unforgivable, LeAnn.
什么
What?
我杀了佐伊·巴恩斯
I killed Zoe Barnes.
你为什么要这么说
Why would you say that?
我只是想保护她
All I ever tried to do was keep her safe.
她说她想就此消失
She said she wanted to be invisible.
我知道这根本不可能
I knew it wasn't possible.
我知道她要消失
I knew that she would only ever go away...
就得我亲自动手
if I made sure of it.
我不信你
I don't believe you.
你当然信
Yes, you do.
相信我  这是我活该
Believe me... I deserve this.
佐伊·巴恩斯落轨被地铁撞死了
Zoe Barnes fell in front of a train.
调查结果是意外事故
It was ruled an accident.
是我把她从站台上推下去的  然后我就走了
I pushed her off the platform and I walked away.
我知道你联系了布莉姬特·柯恩
I know you reached out to Bridget Cohen.
把我肝脏的来头告诉她或是委员会
Telling that committee or her how I got my liver
对政府  对你  都没有一丝好处
is not going to help this administration or you.
我告诉你做什么有好处
But here is what is going to help.
我要你去找委员会
This is what you're going to tell that committee
这么说道格·斯坦普
about Doug Stamper.
你就住这儿
You actually live here?
我不经常住
Well... I'm not here that much.
偶尔让我朋友来住住
I let friends use it now and again.
-谢谢你的谨慎  -应该的
- Thanks for your discretion. - Of course.
我不会待太久
I won't be too long.
你慢慢来
Take your time.
如果需要什么  我随叫随到
If you need anything, I'll be on call.
他是讲道理的
He's reasonable.
是啊  他必须这样
Yeah, he needs to be.
他们也没怎么查
They didn't look that hard.
特勤局知道我没什么好隐瞒的
The Secret Service knows I have nothing to hide.
他就在楼下
He's downstairs.
别客气
Make yourself at home.
我小时候可喜欢捉迷藏了
I used to love to hide as a kid.
我总是藏得非常好
I was really good at it.
我总能找到最隐蔽的藏身处
I could always choose the best places.
从来没被抓到过
Nobody ever found me.
有一次大家干脆不玩了
One time, everybody just gave up.
所以我在那儿躲了整整13个小时
So I stayed put for, like, 13 hours straight.
你想要什么
What do you want?
他说如果我同意  我绝不会后悔的
He said I wouldn't regret it... if I said yes.
弗兰西斯
Francis.
就是想当初  我同意
When I agreed to write the book
写他起家的故事的时候
about his origin story way back when.
那他现在可后悔请你了
Well, he regrets asking you now.
我同意  是因为我总是非常喜欢
I said yes 'cause I have always been a sucker
听别人是怎么讲他们自己的
for what people tell themselves about themselves.
谁还有手稿
Who has the manuscript?
只有你
You do.
出版商呢
And publishers?
还没给
Not yet.
所以你觉得如何
So what did you think?
有好多段落你都划掉了  汤姆
There are huge sections blacked out, Tom.
你把我们描绘成了怪物
You portrayed us like a couple of monsters.
-我没这么写  -你也不用写出来
- I never used that word. - You didn't have to.
我们刚认识时  在从莫斯科回来的飞机上
On the flight back from Moscow, not long after we met...
你和弗兰西斯大吵了一架
you and Francis had a fight.
吵得很凶
A real knock down.
我告诉弗兰西斯我听见了吼声
I told Francis I heard the yelling,
但没听清说什么
but not the words.
但
But...
你说你们杀了人
you said you were murderers.
他说你们是适者生存
He said you were survivors.
我害怕到这里来
I was dreading coming here.
-为什么  -你不能出版  汤姆
- Why? - You can't publish it, Tom.
我也不想
I'd rather not.
那为什么  钱吗
So, what? Money?
对  但是够了
Yeah... but enough.
足够让我消失一阵了
Enough so I can really get lost for a while.
静一静  让我好好想想该何去何从
Buy some time till I figure out what I'm gonna do next.
我们可以商量个对策的
We can figure something out.
当然
I bet.
那些你涂黑的部分
You know, those parts you blacked out, that's...
-除了你我谁都没告诉过  -我知道
- I've never told anyone but you. - I know.
我什么都知道
I know everything.
但你要的不就是这样吗
But isn't that what you wanted?
我想念抚摸你
I miss touching you.
我不知道没有你在身边该如何是好
I don't know how to not be around you.
我无时无刻不想着你
I think of you all the time.
都快要因此而恨你了
It almost makes me hate you for it.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do.
你太美了
You're so beautiful.
-继续说  -不仅是一般的美
- Keep going. - Not just beautiful, beautiful.
美人千千万万
There's lots of people like that.
你美得目眩  克莱尔
You are radiant, Claire.
而且善良  你太善良了
And good. You are so good.
-我不善良  -不  你是善良的
- I'm not good. - Yes, you are.
-你为什么不吻我  -我想看着你
- Why won't you kiss me? - I wanna look at you.
我真想有一天能去格陵兰
I really do wanna go to Greenland one day.
-我们应该去  -别停
- We should go. - Don't stop.
冰天雪地  如此遥远
It's so frozen and remote.
那里的
The way the...
那里的  气味
The way the... Smells before it...
你知道我什么意思吧
The... You know what I mean?
救命  救命
Help. Help.
汤姆
Tom?
死亡人数将近五十万
There are close to half a million dead.
有超过四百万名难民
Over four million refugees,
背井离乡  需要照料的妇女儿童
women and children who have left the region and require care.
流离失所的人至少有一千两百万
At least 12 million displaced people.
无处可去  无家可归的流浪者
Homeless wanderers who no longer belong anywhere.
我们都学过历史
We are all students of history.
叙利亚可是联合国创始国之一
Syria was one of the founding members of the United Nations,
天呐
for God's sakes.
我们是怎么走到今天的
How did we get here?
我们来自最古老的文明之一
We, who sprang from one of the most ancient civilizations?
我们终得承认  和平才是唯一的答案
At some point, we must accept peace as the only answer.
各方必须放下武器  开始和谈
All parties must lay down their arms and begin to talk.
好吧
Okay.
你总能找到我
You were always good at tracking me down.
很不容易
It wasn't easy.
电影院  偶尔的秘密会议
Movie theater, the occasional classified meeting.
我知道你在干什么
I know what you're doing.
这么说有点含糊
Well, that's a bit vague.
你是在给他捣乱  让参议员倒戈
You're sabotaging him. Peeling off senators.
我知道是你干的
I know it's you.
你抽烟的时候要有趣得多
You were much more interesting when you smoked.
我没有
No, I wasn't.
钱不在他那儿  马克
The money's not with him, Mark.
科赫兄弟那些人  华尔街  石油天然气
The... the Koch brother types, Wall Street, oil and gas...
连工人都要抛弃他了
Even labor's walking out on him.
他比你想得要神通广大
He's more resourceful than you think.
没有钱他也做了很多  好吧
He's done a lot without money, okay?
我要你别插手
I want you to back off,
让我应付听证会
let me handle these hearings.
我刚到白宫
I just got to the White House.
我想留下
I intend to stick around.
我不希望他当总统
I don't want him to be president.
-国家需要改变  -好  那么
- The country needs a change. - Okay, so...
有他妻子  就不用找其他人选了
And they don't need to look any further than his wife.
她坚韧又聪明
She's tough, smart.
他也很聪明  但他不可靠
He's smart, too, but he's not reliable.
至于她  你可以跟她合作
Her? You can work with her.
我知道你也清楚这一点
I know you see it, too.
叙利亚  或者满目疮痍的叙利亚
I see a partner when it comes to Syria,
可以成为合作伙伴
or what's left of it.
给我一个
Let me try one of those.
我们就不该
I mean, far be it from us
告诉一个古老的文明怎么处理它的问题
to tell an ancient civilization its business...
但现在  叙利亚是这世界上
but Syria is now basically unrivaled
-最暴力的地方  -我知道
- as the most violent place on the planet. - I know, I know.
我不是说  要拿弗兰克·安德伍德怎么办
I'm not saying what to do with Frank Underwood
不会成为一个巨大的麻烦
is not gonna be a difficult problem.
但  如果我们不在当地立足
But... if we don't establish a presence in the region...
那就太迟了
it's gonna be too late.
-我更想抽根烟  -吐出来吧
- I'd rather have a cigarette. - Spit it out.
让我请你吃晚饭吧
Well... let me buy you dinner or something.
怎么  怎么了
What? What happened? What's the matter?
我抱着那孩子
I had that child in my arms.
我能感觉到她的呼吸
I could feel her breath on me,
但却不敢往下看
but I couldn't look down.
失陪
Excuse me.
喂
Yeah?
20分钟就到
20 minutes away.
-好  我得走了  抱歉  -去吧
- Okay. I have to go. I'm sorry. - Do, please.
我累了  我去睡了
I'm tired. I'm going to bed.
我需要你的服务
I need your services.
天呐
Jesus.
不
No.
马上
Now.
我认为道格·斯坦普杀了佐伊·巴恩斯
I believe Doug Stamper killed Zoe Barnes.
我认为他情绪不稳定
I believe he was unstable
为了弗兰西斯·安德伍德杀了她
and killed her to benefit Francis Underwood.
暂停  不要记录
Stop. Stop it, please? Off the record.
能让我们单独待会儿吗  我再叫你
Can you give us a second? I'll call you back in.
赛斯  这跟贿赂或卡拉比毫无关系
Seth, this has nothing to do with pay for play, or Kalabi,
跟其他任何总统受到的指控都无关
or anything else the president is accused of.
你想干什么
Where are you getting this?
这是我知道的道格的事
This is what I know about Doug.
主席不会允许
The chair will not let you
你在委员会前就此作证的
testify in front of the committee with this.
-我只有这些  -你能证明吗
- This is what I have. - Can you prove any of it?
他暗示他那么做了
He's implied that he did it.
我可以阐述他的行为
I can speak to his behavior.
他做的事
Things that he's done.
你得去找联邦检察官
You need to go to the US attorney.
赛斯  否则  我会去的
Seth, if you don't, I will.
"我告诉总统  国务院追踪了四个
"I told the president there were four men by the same name
同名的男子
the State Department was tracking.
两个在美国境内"
Two in the United States."
这引述自一位资深白宫人士
So said a senior White House source,
由《华盛顿先驱报》刊登的
as quoted in the Washington Herald.
你是否知道这对话
Were you aware of this conversation?
不  先生  不知道
No, sir, I was not.
消息源还称
The source went on.
"我认为总统知道
"I believe the president understood
田纳西州的默罕默德·卡拉比
that the Muhammed Kalabi in Tennessee
并非真正的威胁"
was not a legitimate threat."
这你是否知道
Was this conveyed to you in any way?
还是不知道  先生
Again, no, sir.
委员会依然期待
Still, the committee's looking forward to
杜兰特国务卿就此事作证
Secretary Durant's testimony on this matter.
我不知道国务卿会说什么  但是
I have no idea what the secretary will say or not say, but I...
我对她很尊敬  也祝愿她早日康复
have great respect for her and wish her a speedy recovery.
我们那天是依据
We were operating off of facts and
飞速涌入的事实和报告行动的
reports coming in at an accelerated rate that day.
我再问一次
I'll try this again.
总统是否曾向你暗示
Did the president indicate to you at any time
他知道这并非真正威胁
that he knew this was not a threat?
没有
No.
而且我要说  我很骄傲
And I'd like to point out that I'm proud
今天能在此代表联调局的男男女女
to be representing the men and women of the FBI here today,
他们像以往一样进行了此案的调查
who conducted that investigation as they always do
得力  诚实  而且独立
in a competent, honest, and independent way,
这是联调局的优良传统
in the finest tradition of the FBI.
-是吗  -我们的人尽了职
- Did they? - Our people did their job.
认为联调局会
And it's unthinkable to assume
卷入选举根本是无稽之谈
the FBI would involve itself in an election.
因为此时此刻可能有一个
Because there may be an innocent man
无辜的人正在蹲监狱
sitting in a cell as we speak.
我可以就此发表评论  因为报道中有提及
I can comment on this since it was mentioned in the press.
卡拉比先生的电脑上
Trace amounts of an explosive material
的确发现了痕量爆炸物
were found on Mr. Kalabi's computer.
你是说  总统不知道
Your assertion is that the president was unaware
自己的白宫里都发生了什么
of what was happening in his own White House?
艾丹·麦卡伦是国安局的雇员
Aidan Macallan was an NSA employee,
所以  不  总统不知道他都做了什么
so, no, the president had no idea what he was up to.
老实说  他当时在忙于竞选
Honestly, he was quite busy campaigning.
但他肯定知道麦卡伦先生做的事的影响吧
But surely he knew the effects of Mr. Macallan's work?
这些漏洞
These exploits?
不知道
No.
总统  我是跟着他去巡回过的
The president and... I've been with him out on the stump.
他喜欢跟人握手
He likes to shake hands.
他并不关注社交媒体
He's not paying attention to social media.
哈维小姐  外国情报监视法法庭发布了一则判决
Ms. Harvey, there was a FISA ruling issued,
而安德伍德政府利用它
which the Underwood administration used
来监视美国公民
to spy on American citizens
意在影响选举
for the sake of swaying an election.
罗梅洛议员  艾丹·麦卡伦是个有困扰的人
Congressman Romero, Aidan Macallan was a troubled person.
他的脑子转得很快
His mind worked fast,
恐怕已超出了正常范围
faster than I think anyone's should.
他的企图已被他带入坟墓
What he was up to went to the grave with him.
哈维小姐  少跟我打感情牌
Ms. Harvey, please, spare me the semantics...
-好吧  -我只需要你
- Okay, fine. - I just need you...
他收集数据了吗  是的
Was he collecting data? Yes.
他过界了吗  很可能
Did he cross a line? Most likely.
我去看过他  看他的工作
I did visit with him, checking in on his work.
你见过一屏的代码吗  电脑代码
Have you seen a screen of code? Computer code.
那根本看不懂
It's indecipherable.
赛斯·格雷森怎么最终没作证
Why did Seth Grayson end up not testifying?
无可评价
No comment.
我们听说他的证词
We heard that his testimony
跟总统的幕僚长有关
had to do with the president's chief of staff.
我很欢迎他来我们委员会作证
Who I would welcome testifying in front of our committee.
我敦促道格·斯坦普和其他政府人员
I urge Doug Stamper and the rest of the administration
别再躲在行政特权之后了
to stop hiding behind executive privilege.
我们目前只知道
All we learned so far is that
总统对他的白宫发生的事毫不知情
the president knew nothing about anything going on in his White House.
一共六个人
There were six of them,
他们轮流来
and they all took a turn.
除了罗梅洛
Except for Romero.
他只是看了
He only watched.
至少他是这么跟校长说的
Or... at least that's what he told the dean.
但我知道真相
But I know the real story.
她叫罗谢尔
Her name was, uh, Rochelle.
你不是没有他的把柄吗
I thought you had nothing on this guy.
你知道多久了
How long have you known this?
我是想留到我们需要的时候
I was holding it until... Or, if we needed it.
是你需要的时候吧
No, until you needed it, you mean.
这没什么区别
Look, it makes no difference.
我可能会用  可能不会
I might use it, I might not.
但我还是想作证
But I still wanna testify.
你现在作证
For you to testify now,
抱歉  简直疯了
excuse me for saying it, it's crazy.
你觉得疯了吗  克莱尔
Do you think it's crazy, Claire?
-我想在他面前维护自己  -我们有证人
- I wanna defend myself against this guy. - We have witnesses.
我们的证人  代理人  让他们说
Our witnesses, surrogates. Let it come from them.
我觉得我能赢
I think I can win.
或者我该等到我被参议院抛弃
Or maybe I should wait until I lose the Senate...
我就是觉得还有别的办法
I just think there are other ways...
如果你放弃行政特权
If you give up executive privilege,
我们就丧失了筹码  完全没了
we lose leverage. We lose it all.
告诉主席  我愿作证了
Tell the chair I'm ready to appear.
你的证词可能对你妻子造成的伤害
I mean, the damage your testimony could do to your wife
不值得冒险
is not worth the risk.
我们就是要讨论它的价值
Its worth is what we're here to discuss.
我不喜欢由我来说  但是
I... I don't appreciate being the one to tell you this, but...
你的总统之位已经保不住了
your presidency is beyond repair.
你不知道我接下来要做什么
You don't know what I'm going to do next.
不是这个吗  这才是让你困扰的吧
Isn't that it? Isn't that what really bothers you?
别以为我没从你加入的那一刻
Don't think I haven't been watching you
就在观察你
from the moment you stepped on board.
你满口承诺  戴维斯女士
You're full of promises, Ms. Davis.
麦卡伦的事仍未平息
The information about Macallan is still out there
而艾哈迈迪则神出鬼没
and Ahmadi is, oh, so elusive.
你从走进我家
You've been sabotaging me
就一直在给我捣乱
from the moment you stepped into my house.
你不喜欢我  是吧
You don't care for me very much, do you?
是的
No, I don't.
我一点也不喜欢
I couldn't care less.
但如果你让克莱尔开心  我就开心
But if you make Claire happy, that makes me happy.
如果你能好好帮她
If you can help her,
-那很好  -你愿付出什么
- good. - What's it worth to you?
你打算做什么样的交易
Well, what kind of deal are we talking about?
要我不作证
For me not to testify.
我在华府外有人
Well, I have contacts outside the Beltway.
我可以给你找到各种肥差
I can set you up in any number of lucrative positions.
不  那不够好
No, that's not good enough.
谁都能给我那个
Anyone could offer me that.
你说呢
You tell me.
不不  不能这样
No, no, no. It's not going to work like that.
你说你能为我做什么
You tell me what you can do for me.
我接触过你这样的人
I've been around your kind.
一般没接触到这种深度
Not usually at this level.
但你就是忍不住
But you can't help yourself.
给我开价  戴维斯女士
Make me an offer, Ms. Davis.
你愿为她付出什么
What is she worth to you?
很多
A lot.
那么我是这么想的
So then here's what I'm thinking.
你是否庄严宣誓确认
Do you solemnly swear and affirm
你即将给出的证词是真相
that the testimony you are about to give is the truth,
全部真相  绝无隐瞒
the whole truth, and nothing but the truth?
我宣誓
I do.
请记录
Let the record reflect that
证人给出了肯定回答
the witness has answered in the affirmative.
总统先生  我想感谢你前来作证
Mr. President, I want to thank you for appearing...
希望我们可以为美国人民
and I hope we get to clear some things up
澄清一些事
for the American people.
总统先生  你可以开始
Mr. President, the floor is yours.
你想讲多久都行
You can take as long or as short as you like.
如果你有书面声明
If you have any written statement,
我们会在稍后将它纳入记录
we will include it after and it will be part of the record.
总统先生  请讲
Mr. President, you are recognized.
谢谢  主席先生
Thank you, Mr. Chairman...
也感谢其他委员会成员
and to the other members of this committee.
我今天同意在委员会面前作证
I have agreed to appear before this committee today...
是因为
because...
我有罪
I'm guilty.
我花了30年的人生
Guilty of having spent the last 30 years of my life
在这里
here...
在国会
in this Congress.
在众议院
In this House.
然后成为副总统  总统
Then as vice president and now as president,
只为效力于人民
trying to do the people's work.
委员会指控我犯下了很多事
Now, this committee has accused me of a great number of things.
你们指控我贿赂
You accused me of pay to play.
那么我也指控你们犯下了同样罪行
And so I accuse you of exactly the same.
我还指控你们只为自己的利益行使政治手段
I also accuse you of playing politics only when it suits you.
你们都拿了钱
You're all being paid.
你们都有要效力的主子
You're all serving some master.
你们每个人
Each and every one of you,
你们知道我所言不虚
and you know I know that for a fact.
比如你  罗梅洛议员
You, for example, Congressman Romero...
你扳倒我的不懈努力  是为了正义吗
and your crusade to take me down, is it for justice?
为了国家吗
For the good of the nation?
你真的是想要真相吗
Is the truth what you're really after?
还是为了个人利益
Or is it for some personal gain?
或许是为了填补
Perhaps to try to fill
你很久之前卖掉的
the small hole in your soul
那一块灵魂留下的空洞
that you sold off a long time ago?
-总统先生  -不  不  不
- Mr. President. - No, no, no.
这是我的开场陈述
This is my opening statement,
我要说完
and I will give it in full.
我还没说完  女士们先生们
I am not done, ladies and gentlemen.
你们指控我违反规则
You accuse me of breaking the rules,
我告诉你们  我完全遵守规则
and I tell you, I am playing by the rules.
正是你们和我一起达成的规则
The very rules that you and I all agreed upon.
正是你们和我
The very rules that you and I
一起写的规则
all wrote together.
是的  我非常有罪
So, yes, I'm guilty as hell,
但你们也都有罪
but then so are all of you.
是的  体制有问题
Yes, the system is corrupt,
但你们想要我这样的人守门
but you wanted a guardian at the gate like me.
为什么呢
And why?
因为你们知道
Because you know
我会不惜一切
I will do whatever it takes.
你们都喜欢这样
And you have all enjoyed it,
参与其中  并从中获利
been party to it and benefited by it.
别否认  你喜欢的
Don't deny it. You've loved it.
你并不需要我坚持什么
You don't actually need me to stand for anything.
你只希望我站出来
You just need me to stand.
希望我强势
To be the strong man.
希望我采取行动
The man of action.
天呐  你好喜欢行动和口号
My God, you're addicted to action and slogans.
不管我说了什么
It doesn't matter what I say.
我做了什么
It doesn't matter what I do.
只要我有所作为
Just as long as I'm doing something,
你就乐意跟着走
you're happy to be along for the ride.
老实说  我不怪你
And frankly, I don't blame you.
你生活中有那么多愚蠢和犹豫
With all the foolishness and indecision in your lives,
为什么不要个我这样的人
why not a man like me?
我不道歉
I don't apologize.
最终  我不在意你是爱我还是恨我
In the end, I don't care whether you love me or you hate me,
只要我赢就行
just as long as I win.
结局早被安排好  规则是被操纵的
The deck is stacked. The rules are rigged.
欢迎来到理智时代的终结
Welcome to the death of the Age of Reason.
已经没有是非了
There is no right or wrong. Not anymore.
只有入局
There's only being in...
和出局
and then being out.
所以我不要再参与其中了
So I will not be party to this any longer.
我不要再替你们背负骂名了
I will not wear the target for any of you anymore.
你们都已经利用我太久了
You have all used me far long enough.
所以派对结束  旅程结束
So, the party's over, the ride's done.
我太尊重这一职位
I respect the office too much
不能允许这继续下去
to allow this to continue going on.
所以我要向委员会和全国人民宣布
That's why I am announcing to this committee and to the nation
明晚6点起
that as of 6:00 p.m. tomorrow evening,
我将辞去美国总统一职
I shall resign the office of President of the United States.
秩序
Order!
届时我乐意回答你们的一切问题
And I will be happy to take any questions you may have.
但我的直觉是  已经没那个必要了
But my gut tells me that isn't really going to be necessary.
听证会作证有两个类型
一种要求证人宣誓  宣誓后如果说谎  就是违法行为
另一种不宣誓  有不实之言不用负法律责任
如果被发现宣誓后说谎  可能被国会表决定为"蔑视国会"
但位高权重之人  往往也只受到书面谴责  并不一定真的会被起诉
普通人则不敢冒险
国会有发传票的权力  收到传票的人按法律规定需要服从
但如果不服从  并不会直接受到惩罚
往往是  如果在接受调查时不配合  那么可能会导致司法介入
然后走法律程序  被起诉定罪
同样  如果国会在调查后发现被调查者有违法行为
那么相关的司法部门会随即介入  进行进一步的起诉  定罪
也就是说  国会调查很严重  但并不能代替法律程序